Sets are simple data structures,
集合是非常简单的数据结构
and they have one main use, collecting unique elements.
它的一个主要用途 是收集唯一的独特的元素
Our next data structures,
我们要学习的下一个数据结构
dictionaries, are more flexible.
字典 要更加灵活
Rather than storing single objects like lists and sets do,
它不像列表和集合一样存储单个对象
dictionaries store pairs of elements, keys and values.
字典存储元素对 包括键和值
In this example, we define a dictionary where the keys are
在这个例子中 我们定义了一个字典
element names and their values are there corresponding atomic numbers.
其中键是元素名称 它们的值是相应的原子序数
We can look up values in the dictionary by using square brackets enclosing a key.
我们可以使用括起键的方括号在字典中查找值
We can also insert new values into the dictionary with square brackets.
我们还可以使用方括号在字典中插入新值
Here, we're adding lithium and giving it a value of three.
在这里 我们正在添加锂 lithium 并赋予它三个值
Dictionary keys are similar to list indices.
字典键与列表索引类似
We can select elements from the data structure by putting the key in square brackets.
我们可以通过将键放在方括号中来从数据结构中选择元素
Unlike lists, dictionaries can have keys of any immutable type, not just integers.
与列表不同 字典可以包含任何不可变类型的键 而不仅仅是整数
The element dictionary uses strings for it's keys.
元素字典使用字符串作为其键
However, it's not even necessary for every key to have the same type.
但是 每个键都必须具有相同的类型
We can check whether a value is in a dictionary,
我们可以检查一个值是否在字典中
the same way we check whether a value is in a list or set with the in keyword.
与列表相同 我们通过 in 这个关键字来判断键是否在集合中
We can use in to verify whether a key is in the dictionary before looking it up.
在查找之前 我们可以使用 in 来检验该键是否在字典中
If there's a possibility that the key is not there.
如果想要查找的键可能不在字典中的话
Mithril was not part of our elements dictionary,
秘银（Mithril）不是我们元素字典的一部分
so false is printed.
所以打印结果是 False
Dictionaries have a related method that's also useful.
字典有一个方法也很有用
Get, get looks up values in a dictionary,
Get 在字典中查找值
but unlike square brackets,
但不像方括号
get returns none or a default value of your choice,
Get 返回 None 或者你选择的默认值
if the key is not found.
如果键没有找到
The lithium is not in our dictionary,
锂（lithium）不在我们的字典里
so none is returned and then printed.
所以 None 被返回并打印
If you expect look-ups to sometimes fail,
如果你希望查找在某些情况下失败
get might be a better tool than
Get 可能是一个更好的工具
normal square bracket look-ups because errors can crash your program which isn't good.
常用的方括号查找会因为错误会导致程序崩溃 这不是我们所期望看到的
You can check if a key return none with the is operator,
您可以使用is运算符检查键是否返回none
or you can check for the opposite using is not.
或者你也可以使用 is not 来达到相反的目的
These are called identity operators.
这些被称为恒等式运算符
You will learn more about identity operators and how they differ from using
您将了解有关恒等式运算符的更多信息
these equals two or not equals to comparison operators in the quizzes that follow.
以及它们与后续测验中的这些等于或不等于比较运算符的区别